<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<addons>
    <addon id="repository.sun_sl_repo" name="Sun SL Repository" version="1.0.0" provider-name="SunSL">
        <requires>
            <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0" />
        </requires>
        <extension point="xbmc.addon.repository" name="Sun SL Repository">
            <info compressed="false">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YOURUSERNAME/Sun_SL_Repo/main/addons.xml</info>
            <checksum>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YOURUSERNAME/Sun_SL_Repo/main/addons.xml.md5</checksum>
            <datadir zip="true">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YOURUSERNAME/Sun_SL_Repo/main/</datadir>
            <assets>
                <icon>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YOURUSERNAME/Sun_SL_Repo/main/repository.sun_sl_repo/icon.png</icon>
            </assets>
        </extension>
        <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
            <summary lang="en_GB">Sun SL Repository</summary>
            <description lang="en_GB">Sun SL Repository — Kodi subtitle translation addons. Translate subtitles using Gemini AI or Google Translate directly from the Download Subtitles menu.</description>
            <platform>all</platform>
            <license>GPL-2.0-only</license>
        </extension>
    </addon>
    <addon id="service.subtitles.translator" name="Subtitle Translator" version="1.0.0" provider-name="SunSL">
        <requires>
            <import addon="xbmc.python" version="3.0.0" />
        </requires>
        <extension point="xbmc.subtitle.module" library="service.py" />
        <extension point="xbmc.addon.metadata">
            <summary lang="en_GB">Subtitle Translator — Google Translate + Gemini AI</summary>
            <description lang="en_GB">
Translate any subtitle directly from the Download Subtitles menu using Google Translate (free, no setup) or Gemini AI (more accurate, natural dialogue).

HOW TO USE:
1. Play a video in Kodi
2. Press T on keyboard (or open OSD and tap Subtitles - Download Subtitles)
3. Select Subtitle Translator from the provider list
4. Choose Browse for subtitle file or Browse Kodi temp folder
5. Pick your SRT file
6. Select your target language from the popup list
7. Translation runs automatically and subtitle loads into the video

SETTINGS (tap Settings inside the subtitle menu):
- Gemini API Key: paste your free key here for better quality translation
- Gemini Model: choose the model that fits your usage
- Language: remembers your last used language automatically

GEMINI AI SETUP (optional but recommended):
1. Go to aistudio.google.com
2. Sign in with your Google account
3. Click Get API key and create a new key
4. Open Kodi - Download Subtitles - Subtitle Translator - Settings
5. Paste the key into Gemini API Key field
6. Choose a model based on your needs

GEMINI FREE MODELS:
- Gemini 2.5 Flash: Best quality, 250 requests per day, around 10 movies per day
- Gemini 2.5 Flash-Lite: Good quality, 1000 requests per day, around 43 movies per day
- Gemini 2.5 Pro: Highest quality, 100 requests per day, around 4 movies per day
- Daily limits reset at midnight Pacific Time
- If limit is reached the addon automatically falls back to Google Translate

WITHOUT GEMINI KEY:
The addon uses Google Translate automatically. No setup needed, completely free, works for all languages.

SUPPORTED FORMATS:
- SRT subtitle files
- ZIP files containing SRT (browse inside the ZIP natively)

100+ languages supported.
    </description>
            <platform>all</platform>
            <license>GPL-2.0-only</license>
        </extension>
    </addon>
</addons>